Dominik Lenda

Wrocław, Dolnośląskie, Poland



dominik.lenda@protonmail.com



linkedin.com/in/dominik-lenda-a0097b200

Summary

Hi, I'm Dominik.

I'm changing my profession from psychological researcher to cloud engineer. Every day I document my learnings on Twitter.

Psychological science is full of fascinating questions and research problems. I've had an exciting opportunity to explore and apply tools, theories of decision making. However, I realized the most interesting to me in my scientific journey was problem-solving, especially software development.

That's why I'm getting into IT; I need more problem-solving. I have experience in a few tech-related fields, for example, data analysis and web development. I had a gist of many software development areas, and familiarity with multiple programming languages such as Python, R. However, the most unknown and exotic to me was cloud computing. Out of pure curiosity, I've started exploring the Cloud, and after a few months, all I can say is, I love it.

Currently, I participate in the #100DaysOfCloud, the challenge of learning cloud computing 100 days in a row. Each day I document what I've learned on Twitter. I've got Azure Fundamentals certification by passing the AZ-900 exam. I'm preparing for other certifications such as AZ-104 and learning Linux administration. My main goal is to build things in the cloud, and the certification journey is only the help to navigate it. My first cloud project was resume in Azure with a visit counter that uses serverless Azure Functions. I cannot wait for more projects!

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

My current interests:

- •# Microsoft Azure
- # Linux Administration
- •# Cloud Computing
- # Python
- # Git

My planned interests:

- •# Automation
- # Infrastructure as Code (IaC)
- # CI/CD
- •# Serverless
- # System Architecture

Experience



Principal Investigator

Uniwersytet SWPS

Sep 2018 - Present (2 years 11 months +)

I conducted a €40,000 research grant project on cognitive underpinnings of experience-based choices.

Main responsibilities:

- building statistical models,
- manipulating data in R,
- preparing computer-based experiments in Python,
- writing proposals, publications.

📭 Data Analyst

Pogotowie Statystyczne

Mar 2020 - Jul 2021 (1 year 5 months)

I was a data analyst and R programmer.

Main responsibilities:

- contacting clients,
- programming in R,
- preparing statistical models,
- applying statistical inference in Bayesian and frequentist methodology,
- writing reports of data analysis for scientific publications.

Web Developer

Curate Science

Dec 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 2 months)

I worked as a web developer on a web application that organizes, sorts, categorizes scientific articles, having them in one place. The final goal of this enterprise was to promote open science practices.

My main responsibilities:

- web application development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React;
- web scrapping metadata of scientific journals using Python, BeautifulSoup, and Scrapy;
- interacting with Google Cloud Platform;
- Git.

Education



Uniwersytet SWPS

Magister (Mgr), Badania i psychologia eksperymentalna 2014 - 2019

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Microsoft Azure • Cloud Computing • Project Management • Quantitative Research • Statistical Data Analysis • Obróbka danych • SQL • Git • Generic Programming

Honors & Awards



Scholarship of Minister of Science and Higher Education in Poland - Ministry of

Science and Higher Education, Poland

Dec 2018

Scholarship for outstanding achievements awarded to students.

Laureate of the Diamond Grant award - Ministry of Science and Higher Education, Poland

Jul 2018

I was a laureate of the 7th edition of the Diamond Grant programme. Diamond Grants are scholarships for outstanding students-researchers in Poland. Only about 200 students from the whole country and all fields of study get this award.

Laureate of the "The Best of The Best! 3.0" scholarship - Ministry of Science and Higher Education, Poland

Aug 2018

I won the "The Best of The Best! 3.0" scholarship. It allowed me to conduct research on statistical practices in psychological science and show my work during a 31st Annual Convention of Psychological Science in Washington, D.C.

Arctic Code Vault Contributor - GitHub

The badge is a way to honor open-source contributions stored in a data repository kept in facilities located 250 meters deep in the permafrost of an Arctic mountain.